Finding Aid for Warren P. Lombard pamphlets and reprints, 1885-1926
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Warren P. Lombard pamphlets and reprints 1885-1926
Lombard, Warren P. (Warren Plimpton), 1855-1939.
1 box
[737] DA 2; L841; P186
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was accumulated from different sources.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Warren P. Lombard was a professor of physiology at the University of Michigan.
This collection of pamphlets and reprints of writings of Warren P. Lombard was accumulated from various sources. The collection has been arranged alphabetically by title.
- Pamphlets and Reprints
  - Alterations in the strength which occur during fatiguing voluntary muscular work. 1893 (Box 1)
  - The blood pressure in the arterioles, capillaries, and small veins of the human skin. 1912 (Box 1)
  - Der Blutdruck in den Kapillaren und kleinen Venen der menschlichen Haut. 1911 (Box 1)
  - Draft of plan to make it easier for medical practitioners to enlist in the army or navy. 1917 (Box 1)
  - The duration of the systole of the left ventricle of man. 1926 (Box 1)
  - The effect of fatigue on voluntary muscular contractions. 1890 (Box 1)
  - Effect of position of body on the length of systole and diastole and rate of pulse in man. 1919 (Box 1)
  - Effect of posture on the length of the systole of the human heart. 1919 (Box 1)
  - Effect of pulse rate on the length of the systoles and diastoles of the normal human heart in the standing position. 1919 (Box 1)
  - Effet de la fatigue sur la contraction muscular volontaire. 1890 (Box 1)
  - "Greetings from universities and colleges of the Middle West" in The centennial of Hobart College, 1822-1922. 1922 (Box 1)
  - Henry Sewall and the department of physiology. 1909 (Box 1)
  - Is the "Knee-kick" a reflex act? 1887 (Box 1)
  - The life and work of Carl Ludwig. 1916 (Box 1)
  - The mechanical effects produced by the contraction of individual muscles of the thigh of the frog. 1907 (Box 1)
  - A method of recording changes in body weight which occur within short intervals of time. 1906 (Box 1)
  - A new form of piston recorder and some of the changes of the volume of the finger which it records. 1899 (Box 1)
  - On the nature of the knee-jerk. undated (Box 1)
  - Die raumliche und zeitliche aufeinanderfolge reflectorisch contrahirter muskeln. 1885 (Box 1)
  - Re-enforcement and inhibition of nervous processes. 1901 (Box 1)
  - A review of the life of Ludwig. 1905 (Box 1)
  - Secondary rhythms of the normal heart. 1899 (Box 1)
  - Some of the influences which affect the power of voluntary muscular contractions. 1892 (Box 1)
  - The tendon action and leverage of two-joint muscles of the hind leg of the frog with special reference to the spring movement. 1903 (Box 1)
  - The variations of the normal knee-jerk. 1887 (Box 1)